# MICHAEL CHANG

(408) 480-6649 | michaelchang@alumni.purdue.edu | Livermore, CA | mchang-orz.github.io | @Michael Chang

## CAREER SUMMARY

I am a pipeline / lighting td, with 3 years cumulative experience working the film and post-production industry. I am mostly focused on the technical side of things, working with artists and other technical directors on creating useful tools, scripts, and workflows to help them in the creation of major motion pictures and shows. I am open to expanding my horizons, and look forward for any opportunities in other fields where I can apply my expertise and skills to contribute to new exciting projects.

#### **EXPERTISE**

scripting | tool workflow documentation | lighting | pipeline development | technical support for tooling | version control

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Maya | Nuke | Renderman / Arnold | Python | C/C++ | USD | Blender | Unreal Engine | Godot | Houdini | Git

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## PIPELINE TD| Company 3 Method | Remote

Aug 2021 - June 2023

- Helped develop workflow and VFX delivery tools for a budding pipeline due to merger between companies.
- Assisted artists in multiple time zones with troubleshooting shot deliveries and renders.
- Wrote and documented tools and processes for artists to use as guidelines for usage of internal shot management system.

# FREELANCER | Zoetic Media LLC | Remote

July 2021 - Oct 2021

- Contracted as freelancer to create VFX for animated short film Mano.
- Using Houdini and Unreal Engine, created smoke and fire simulations that were integrated into Unreal
- Used the Blueprints system to setup timings and emitters for baked out simulations for the sequencer for the film.

### ASSISTANT TD | Alchemic LTD | San Rafael, CA

Apr 2019 – Oct 2019

- Created pipeline tools and scripts to help with automating a taxing manual process of sending working shots between artists, as well as uploading deliveries to and from the render farm.
- As a lighter, worked on lighting scenes for an experimental music video for ABBA, with realistic, 3d modelled de-aged versions of band members. I mostly lit shots with Björn and Agnetha.
- Automated slap comp and dailies delivery system to work overnight without supervision, speeding up the number of shots we
  could show daily to clients.

#### **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR'S DEGREE | Computer Graphics Technology | Purdue University

2014 - 2018

## INTERESTS

Gaming | sailing | practical effects | making games | 3d printing | volunteer video post-production | learning to code